Guide to the Walter Gardner Hall Papers, 1923-1990 MS 280
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Walter Gardner Hall papers
1923-1990
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Hall, Walter G. (Walter Gardner)
MS 280
31.5 Linear Feet (22 boxes)
Correspondence, memos, oral history interviews, political pamphlets, broadsides, and clippings, relating to Hall's involvement with the Texas and national Democratic parties and soil and water conservation and improvement. Correspondents include Minnie Fisher Cunningham, Hubert H. Humphrey, Lyndon B. Johnson, Sam Rayburn, Jim Wright, and Ralph Yarborough.
Biographical Note
Walter Gardner Hall was born in Houston, Texas on May 30, 1907. His parents, Samuel Emery and Emma Belle Gardner Hall, moved from Illinois to the Texas Gulf Coast in 1898. His family farmed and ran a cafe before his father went to work as a mechanic for the Houston Streetcar Company and later the Interurban Company. In about 1913, Hall and his family moved to League City, only to return to Houston in 1915. In 1919 the Halls moved once again to League City and acquired a ten-acre farm, while Samuel Hall continued to work for the Interurban Company.
Hall enrolled in Rice Institute in 1924 as, he once said, "the greenest freshman that ever entered." When reflecting on his life, Hall has always pointed to his experiences at Rice and his association with such professors as Radoslav A. Tsanoff as vital components of whatever political and economic success he might have had in his life. After his graduation in 1928, Hall went to work for the Texas Company as cashier at a clay mine in Fayette County. Two years later, Hall was transferred to Houston. In January of 1931, in the midst of an ever-worsening depression, Hall resigned from the Texas Company because he believed that the company's management had treated unfairly a friend and fellow employee. He accepted the position of cashier of the Citizens State Bank of League City (a job he had earlier refused) and by 1935 had convinced the owners of the bank to move to Dickinson. In 1943, Hall and his wife, Helen Lewis, whom he had married in 1927, bought controlling interest in the Citizens State Bank of Dickinson. Later, as the Halls and their community prospered, they took over the Alvin State Bank, the Leaque City State Bank, and the Webster State Bank. They also invested in real estate, established several insurance agencies, and acquired controlling interest in Sentinel National Life Insurance Company.
Beginning in the late 1930's, Walter Hall took an increasing interest in politics. He supported President Franklin D. Roosevelt fervently at a time when many Texas Democrats were becoming increasingly estranged from the President. In the mid 1940's, Hall emerged as a leader of the Liberal Democrats in Texas. He helped Lyndon B. Johnson win the crucial Senate election of 1948 and later aided in the election of Senator Ralph W. Yarborough. At the historic 1968 Democratic convention in Chicago, he was a strong supporter of Hubert Humphrey. Although his candidates often lost closely contested elections, Hall continued to support the Democratic Party, particularly the liberal wing of the party, throughout the 1950's, 60's and 70's. Hall died March 12, 2000.
Scope and Contents
Walter Gardner Hall has been a man of many parts--most of them seemingly incongruous. He has been a successful banker and a champion of the liberal wing of the Texas Democratic Party. He has had important social and business ties with the conservative Houston establishment and at the same time has been a close friend of such anti-establishment figures as John Henry Faulk. Through the political wars of the 1950's and 1960's, Hall managed to remain on good terms personally and politically with both Lyndon B. Johnson and Ralph W. yarborough, the oft-feuding leaders of the Texas Democrats on a national level. Within the 25 shelf feet of the Hall Papers there is a record of these diverse associations.
Contained within these papers as well is much information on the men and women with whom Hall corresponded. Among the most notable politicians are Lyndon Johnson, Ralph Yarborough, Sam Rayburn, Minnie Fisher Cunningham, Jim Wright, and Hubert Humphrey. Hall often served as an access route from the people of the Gulf Coast to these politicians, and his letters to the lesser-known folk of his area are equally interesting. Walter Hall, though, has been more than a political animal; his papers reflect extremely close ties with his sons and with friends such as J. R. Parten, George Heap Alexander, W. A. Cooper, Fagan Dickson, and Ralph Yarborough.
Besides speaking of politics and Hall's feelings for other human beings, these papers say much about Walter Hall himself. Hall is the piece of the puzzle which makes these incongruous parts fit together into an understandable whole. His ability to accept divergent opinion if honestly held and to work within the practical limits of a situation reveal some of the reasons for his political and economic success. At the same time, his political values and his position in the midrange between political officials and the voting public illustrate why the American system of government has worked as well as it has.
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions on access to these papers or the accompanying oral interviews.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Acquisition Information
Through the generosity of Walter G. Hall and Rice alumnus Ellis Rudy ('51), the Hall Papers were acquired and funds provided for their processing.
Arrangement
The Hall Papers have been divided into nine topical segments, and one addendum segment. Some of these series have been further divided into subtopics. Within each topic and subtopic a chronological order has been followed. Series VIII, the Oral Interviews, contains tapes of interviews with Walter G. Hall and transcripts of these interviews.
General note
Portions of this collection are available online at https://scholarship.rice.edu/handle/1911/37266.
General
Note to Researchers: In most cases it should be clear to researchers which portion of the Hall Papers best suits their needs. Those interested in Sam Rayburn, for example, should begin with Series V. In some cases, however, letters or other documents dealt with more than one of the major topics. A letter from Sam Rayburn or about Sam Rayburn often contained information on Lyndon Johnson and the Democratic Party. Whenever possible duplicates of these letters were put under both topics. Obviously only the most important and significant of these letters were duplicated, so researchers should not neglect other applicable sections of the Hall Papers.
Hall's personal correspondence also often contains his or his friends' and families' thoughts on the political situation of the day. If his friends were not major politicians and if the bulk of their letters were not political in nature, these series of letters to and from Walter Hall were placed under Personal Correspondence.
What follows is a guide to the Hall Papers which lists the contents of the papers according to the heading of the files within the boxes.
Index Terms
Subjects
Environment; Water conservation; Soil conservation; Political parties; Water; Politics and government
Places
United States; Texas
Subjects (Persons)
Rayburn, Sam; Wright, Jim; Humphrey, Hubert H. (Hubert Horatio); Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines); Yarborough, Ralph Webster; Hall, Walter G. (Walter Gardner); Cunningham, Minnie Fisher
Subjects (Corporations)
Democratic Party (Tex.); Democratic Party (U.S.)
- Series I: Personal Papers, 1923-1979
  - Subseries A: Biographical Material
    - WGH high school graduation invitations, 1923-24 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Rice Institute ballot and broadside/student election, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Article on WGH in Texas Observer, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Interview of WGH by Connie Simpson - typescript, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Biographical data on WGH, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Awards, Date? (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Biographical sketch for R. W. Yarborough, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Article on WGH in the Texas Observer, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - WGH biographical material - newspaper clippings, 1950s (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - WGH biographical material - newspaper clippings, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Biographical sketch for Babe Schwartz, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Inbetween re WGH, 1977-79 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Subseries B: Personal Correspondence, (1942-1978)
    - Personal correspondence re possible military service, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Personal correspondence, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Personal correspondence, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Personal correspondence, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Personal correspondence, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Personal correspondence, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Galveston Broadcasting Co., 1947-48 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Personal correspondence, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Personal correspondence, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Personal correspondence, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Personal correspondence, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Personal correspondence, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Personal correspondence, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Personal correspondence, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Personal correspondence, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Personal correspondence, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Personal correspondence, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Personal correspondence, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Personal correspondence, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Personal correspondence, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Personal correspondence, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Personal correspondence, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Personal correspondence with Fagan Dickson, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Personal correspondence, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Personal correspondence with Fagan Dickson, 1963-64 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Personal correspondence, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Personal correspondence, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Personal correspondence with Fagan Dickson, 1965-66 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Personal correspondence, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Personal correspondence with Fagan Dickson, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Personal correspondence, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Personal correspondence, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Personal correspondence, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Personal correspondence, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Personal correspondence, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Rice University re personal correspondence, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Personal correspondence re Philosophical Society of Texas, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Personal correspondence, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Personal correspondence, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Personal correspondence, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Personal correspondence, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Personal correspondence, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Subseries C: Speeches, (1949-1979)
    - Material for a speech on petroleum and natural gas, 1949-55 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Speeches against McCarthyism, 1951-54 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Background material on Liberals and Democrats, 1950-67 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - WGH, undated and untitled speech, 1950s (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - WGH - notes for speeches, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - WGH, Agricultural Economy, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Background material for speeches on constitutional rights - voting, 1955-65 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - WGH, keynote address before D.O.T. Convention, May 31, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Background material for speeches on international relations, 1958-62 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Speech by WGH for Farm-City Week, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - WGH, It Could Be So, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - WGH speech at Yarborough dinner, May 23, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Background for speeches - statements by RWY, 1959-60 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Background material for speeches on banking, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Background material for speeches on agriculture, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - WGH - introduction of Don Yarborough, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - WGH, What's Right with LBJ, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - WGH - graduation address, Univ. of Houston at Clear Lake City, May 15, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Comments by WGH and Helen Hall at dedication ceremonies of the Walter and Helen Hall Environmental Health Center, Jan. 12, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Series II: The Democratic Party, 1944-1976
  - Subseries A: Party Politics, (1944-1973)
    - Local patronage; personal requests, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Galveston Co. tax re-evaluation, April - Oct., 1944 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - WGH - Hon. J. J. Mansfield re Party politics and meeting between the two, Aug. 1944 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Texas Party politics - Regulars vs. Loyalists, Summer 1944 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - State Democratic Convention - Sept. 12 and 13, 1944, Aug./Sept. 1944 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - State newspapers - organization of Progressive Democratic Newspaper, Sept. 1944 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Minutes of the meeting of the Democratic Executive Committee, Sept. 25, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Democratic organization in Ft. Bend County, Sept. 1944 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Endorsements of the Democratic ticket for publicity, Oct. 1944 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - 1944 Roosevelt - Truman Campaign - Democratic Party, Fall 1944 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Campaign finances, Nov. 1944 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Re Democratic Party and Nov. 7, 1944 victory, Nov./Dec. 1944 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Contribution of $500.00 and over to American Democratic National Committee, Dec. 1944 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Contributions to the 1944 Campaign in the State of Texas of $500.00 or over (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Letters of thanks from WGH for aid in the campaign, Dec. 5, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - WGH - Harry L. Seay re victory in Texas, Dec. 1944 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Re Jan. 10, 1945 meeting of the State Executive Committee, Dec. 1944 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Southern Conference for Human Welfare, April 1945 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Local patronage and personal requests, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Moore Senate Bill 165 - re primary election laws, Spring 1945 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Jefferson Day dinner, Aug. 18, 1945 - Austin, Texas, Spring/Summer 1945 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - WGH - Harry L. Seay re patronage and the Texas Regulars, Summer, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - WGH - Wright Patman re attempts of Texas Regulars to re-enter the Party, Aug./Sept. 1945 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Meeting of precinct chairman - Hall's senatorial district 17, Fall 1945 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - State Democratic Party organization and fund raising, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Mainland Chamber of Commerce, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Galveston Co. tax re-evaluation, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Attorney General's opinion on exemption for veterans and elections, Jan. 1946 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Wright Patman, A Guide for Texas Candidates, Voters and Election Officials, and for State, District, County and Precinct Officers, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Democratic State Executive meeting, Feb. 22, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Harry Seay - WGH re state party, Jan. - March, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Local patronage and personal requests, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Fund raising, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - re Galveston Co. Democratic organization, Spring/Summer 1946 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - WGH - Guy Jackson re Democratic Party and Texas Water Conservation Association, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Democratic State Executive Committee meeting June 10, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Democratic candidates for state office, April - June 1946 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Galveston County Convention - Aug. 3, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Judge Earl P. Hall and Democratic candidate for a judicial vacancy, Summer/Fall 1946 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - State Democratic Convention in San Antonio, Sept. 10, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - WGH - Harry L. Seay re San Antonio Convention - Texas Regulars and Executive Committee, Sept./Oct. 1946 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Mainland Chamber of Commerce, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Galveston Co. tax re-evaluation, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Political correspondence, Jan. - Dec. 1947 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Galveston Co. tax re-evaluation, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - WGH - Dr. Rufus C. Harris re freedom of thought and expression; Henry Wallace, Nov. 1947 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Efforts to abolish the poll tax, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - State politics and political opinions, Jan. - March 1948 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Waco meeting of Truman Democrats, April 1948 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Precinct conventions - Galveston Co., Spring 1948 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - State Convention at Brownwood on May 25, May/June 1948 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Secret Ballot Bill, Summer 1948 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - State party politics, Summer 1948 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - State Democratic Convention - executive committee, Sept. 1948 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Resolution adopted by State Democratic Convention, Ft. Worth, Sept. 14, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Truman - Barkley Campaign, Sept. - Oct. 1948 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Democratic Party organization, Nov./Dec. 1948 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Olin Culberson - WGH - depletion of oil and gas in Texas, Dec., 1948 - Jan., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Sam D. W. Low dinner, May 3, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - State Democratic Executive Committee - WGH chairman, Finance Committee, Jan. - Dec. 1949 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Texas and Galveston Co. politics, Feb. - Dec. 1949 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - H.B. 3 - State Texas, House of Representatives, Feb. 1949 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Library wing for the Alamo - H.B. 21, Feb. 1949 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Resolutions of the State Democratic Executive Committee, Feb. 23, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - re Texas Senate Bill 98 - salary increases for teachers in state colleges, Feb. 1949 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Registration system instead of a poll tax, Feb. 1949 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Appointment of Robert S. Calvert as State Comptroller, Feb. 1949 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Sam D. W. Low - WGH re Low's appointment as Collector of Customs at Galveston, Feb. 1949 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - State Democratic Executive Committee meeting, Feb. 23, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - re Wright Patman - WGH - Wright Morrow as a national committeeman, Feb. 1949 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Limiting the transport of natural gas out of Texas, March 1949 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Appointment of Ed Smith as a federal judge, June 1949 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Death of Tom Tyson - Appointment of his replacement as Secretary of State Democratic Executive Comm., June 1949 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - State Democratic Party, Jan. - Oct. 1950 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - State Democratic Executive Committee - WGH chairman, Finance Committee, Feb. - Oct. 1950 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - William H. Kittrell - WGH re oil and gas; politics, Feb. 1950 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Galveston Co. Democratic Convention, July 29, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - WGH - U.S. Senate Resolution 302 - health insurance, July, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - WGH's preferred candidates in the Democratic primary, July, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Precinct conventions, July 1950 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Democratic Party run-off, Aug. 26, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Democratic primary, July 1950 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Brazoria Co. Democratic Party, Aug. 1950 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Texas Bankers Association and candidates for the State Legislature, June 1950 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - McAllen meeting - Democratic Executive Committee - resolutions, Feb. - March, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Galveston Co. Democratic Party, March - July, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Jefferson - Jackson Day dinner, April 1950 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Tarrant Co. Democratic Party, April 1950 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - State Convention in Mineral Wells on Sept. 12, 1950 - preliminary correspondence, April - Aug. 1950 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - State Convention in Mineral Wells on Sept. 12, 1950, Sept. 1950 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Vacancy in the 67th District Court - Tarrant Co., Sept. 1950 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Marion Storm Memorial Committee, Sept. - Oct. 1950 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - CIO compiled - Voting Record of the Texas Delegation to the U.S. Congress, 1949 - 1951 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Marion Storm Memorial Fund, Jan. - Oct. 1951 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - State Democratic Executive Committee, Feb. - Dec. 1951 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Texas House Bills re banking - 51; 713, Feb. 1951 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Texas House Bill 189 - insurance, Feb. 1951 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Appointment of Sam Low to Court of Customs and Patent Appeals, March 1951 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Mrs. Raymond F. Norris to Mr. Paul Harvey re Democratic Party, March 4, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Ed Hawes; redistricting of Galveston Co. area, March - May 1951 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - WGH - Margaret Reading re Texas Social and Legislative Conference, March - Sept. 1951 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - WGH - Margaret Reading re education; MacArthur; LBJ, May 1951 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Natural gas reserves in Texas, May 1951 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Possible visit of General Marshall to Houston, May - June 1951 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - WGH - Byron Skelton re House Bill 6; Presidential politics in Texas, June 1951 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Republican - Dixiecrat Alliance for 1952, Aug. 1951 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - WGH - Lillian and Jud Collier re House Bill 6; Texas Democratic Club, Aug. 1951 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Capital Comment by William M. Boyle, Jr., chairman, Democratic National Committee re Joe McCarthy, Aug. 1951 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - WGH - Tom McCormick - labor's opinion of farmers, Sept. 1951 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Criticisms of WGH, Truman and equal rights for blacks, Sept. - Oct. 1951 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Loyal Democrats of Texas, Sept. - Dec. 1951 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - WGH - Lillian Collier re Democratic Party in Texas; LBJ; Shivers, Oct. 1951 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Speech of Harrington Wimberly, Commissioner, Federal Power Commission, Oct. 1951 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Oscar Dancy to Harry Seay re Walter Hall, Oct. 15, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - WGH - Don Ellinger re Loyal Democrats, Oct. 1951 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Telegram to Harry L. Seay re Governor's plea for uninstructed delegation, Oct. 1951 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Loyal Democrats - political meeting with Sec. of Ag. Brannan, Oct. 13, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - New Texas election laws, Oct. 1951 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Notes for a speech at Oct. 13-14, 1951 meeting (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Telegrams to Pres. Truman urging appointment of India Edwards as Chairman National Democratic Committee, Oct. 1951 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Position of Gov. Shivers in the Democratic Party and his support of Democratic candidates, Oct. 1951 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Manual of election procedures, Oct. 1951 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - J.J. Hickman - WGH re WGH speaking for Texas State Industrial Union Council, Oct. 1951 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - WGH - India Edwards re Wright Morrow; National Democratic Party, Oct. - Nov. 1951 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - WGH - Daniel Delano - Harry Seay re electing Loyal Democrats, Oct. - Nov. 1951 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Organization of the Loyal Democrats - selection of WGH as chairman, Oct. - Nov. 1951 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - How the Republican Party Lost its Future by Walter Prescott Webb, Oct. 1951 (Box 4, Folder 54)